Guide to the Arthur Few academic records, 1967-2006 UA 191
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Arthur Few academic records
1967-2006
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Few, Arthur
UA 191
10.5 Linear Feet (21 boxes)
Academic papers of Dr. Arthur Few, physicist at Rice University, including his journal articles and other publications, his class notes and lectures, and papers regarding Martel College at Rice University.
Biographical Sketch
Arthur Few was a Professor of Physics and Environmental Science at Rice University from 1970-2008. He received his PhD from Rice University in 1969. He and his wife, Joan, served as Baker College's Masters from 1994-1999, then as the Masters of Martel College from Martel's founding in 2000 until Dr. Few's retirement in 2008. Dr. Few is one of the leading authorities in weather and astronomical physics. His many research projects included research regarding the acoustical properties of thunder, the global electrical current, and electrical currents at the South Pole.
Scope and Contents
Dr. Arthur Few's journal articles and other publications, including a VHS on which he collaborated; his class notes and lectures, including overhead projector transparencies, projector slides, and film; and materials regarding Martel College, including a VHS by a Martel student.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research. Restricted items in this collection are marked in the inventory. Please contact the Woodson Research Center for more information. 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored off-site at the Library Service Center. Please request this material via woodson@rice.edu or call 713-348-2586.
Acquisition Information
Collection was donated by Dr. Arthur Few. Delivered by Dr. Few on 4-11-08, 5-9-08, and 6-13-08.
Arrangement
Materials are organized into three series:
Series I: Articles and Other Publications, 1967-2004
Series II: Class Notes and Lectures, 1972-2006
Series III: Martel College, 2000-2005
Related Materials
See Few, Arthur, Information Files, Woodson Research Center.
Index Terms
Subjects
Education; Science; Universities and colleges
Document Types
publications; lecture notes
Places
Rice University
Subjects (Persons)
Few, Arthur
- Series I: Articles and Other Publications, 1967-2004
  - PhD Thesis - Early Draft (pencil) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - PhD Thesis - Early Annotated Draft (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - PhD Thesis - Published 1968; folder 1 of 2 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - PhD Thesis - Published 1968; folder 2 of 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Contributions to Books and Periodicals, Book and Meeting Reviews, Conference Proceedings: 1969-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: 1969-1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Journal Articles: 1967-1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Review on "A Dominant 200-Hertz Peak in the Acoustic Spectrum of Thunder" - Review by Myron Plooster, NCAR (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Journal Articles: 1985-1989 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Special Publications: 1968-1981 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Newspapers/Magazines Referencing Dr. Few (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Abstracts from the VI International Conference on Atmospheric Electricity; folder 1 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Abstracts from the VI International Conference on Atmospheric Electricity; folder 2 of 2 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Acoustic Radiations from Lightning (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - AGU - Fall 1988 Presentation (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - AGU Paper – Slides, Figures (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Alumni College 2004 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Cloud Electricity - Space Physics and Astronomy Colloquium (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - "Cloud Electricity" - Scientific American 1976 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Conference on Cloud Physics and Atmospheric Electricity - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - CRC Handbook of Atmospherics - 1982 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Duct Formation - 1988 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Energy Use by Humans - 1995-1998 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Factor of 2 - 1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Formation, Nature, and Mobility of Ions of Atmospheric Importance" – Review Paper by Mohnen (1977) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Franklin, Benjamin Presentation (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Global Electricity - 1991 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Global Electricity - 1998; folder 1 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Global Electricity - 1998; folder 2 of 2 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Global Electricity Presentation (South Pole) - AGU 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - IEEE Presentation - Nov. 1982 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Infrasonic Thunder - VII International Conference on Atmospheric Electricity (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Lightning Model (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Lightning Safety - 1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - LIPTIC on CRAYLIB - Nov. 1979 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - MCC Model - data (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Mitchell Prize Laureates - 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Modeling the Earth (VHS) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Quest for a Sustainable Society - 1981 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Report to NASA - 1979: "Electrostatic Protection of the Solar Power Satellite and Rectenna" (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Report to NASA - 1981: "Summary Report of Studies Conducted as a Search for Physical Mechanisms Relating Solar Variability and the Troposphere" (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Review of NASA Proposal - 1998 - Development of Wetland Education Workshops (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Review of "The Interaction of a Dipolar Thunderstorm with its Global Electrical Environment" - 1984 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Report on a Critical Review of Solar-Terrestrial Physical Connective Chains - April 1979 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Rice Center for Community Design and Research (RCCD+R) Communications - 1973 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - RCCD+R Climatological Data (Local) and Substation Summaries: 1972 - (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - RCCD+R Climatological Studies (Special) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - RCCD+R Climate Sources; folder 1 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - RCCD+R Climate Sources; folder 2 of 2 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - RCCD+R Hurricanes: 1973 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - RCCD+R Hurricanes: 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - RCCD+R Hurricanes: Chambers II - 1976 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - RCCD+R Texas Coast Project - 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Single Storm data (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - South Pole Project: 1990 - 1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - South Pole Project: 1990- (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - South Pole Project: 1992- (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - South Pole Project: 1993- (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - South Pole Project: AGU Poster, Photos - 1994 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Report on South Pole Magnetic Field Measurements (1997) (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - South Pole Project: Journal with Photos; correspondence - 1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - South Pole Project Presentation (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - South Pole Project Presentation: "Field Calibration of Electric Field Meters" (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - South Pole Weather: 1991 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Thunder: photos, figures, sources (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Thunder Article - McGraw-Hill: 1992 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Thunderstorm Electricity (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - USA-USSR Symposium 1981: "The Effects of Solar Variability on Climate" (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Series II: Class Notes and Lectures, 1972-2006
  - Note Fragments (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - BAKE 201 - 1999 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - BAKE 205 - 1999 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - BAKE 205 - Shakespeare/London Fieldtrip - 1999 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - BAKE 302/303 - Spring 1998 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - BAKE 303 - Spring 1998 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - BAKE 303 - Arizona Field Trip - 1998 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Biosphere 2 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - BROWN 348: Global Change Issues - Spring 1990; folder 1 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - BROWN 348 - Spring 1990; folder 2 of 2 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Global Warming (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - EE 307 - Fall 1973 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - ELEC 308b/MECH 378b - Spring 1977 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - ENVI 404b - Spring 1973/SPAC 346 - Spring 1988 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - ENVI 404b - 1974 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - LOVE 201/BAKE 202 - Fall 1997; folder 1 of 4 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - LOVE 201 - Fall 1997; folder 2 of 4 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - LOVE 201; folder 3 of 4 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - LOVE 201; folder 4 of 4 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - LOVE 201 - Field Trip to S. TX Project Electric Generating Station; 11-97 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Nitrogen (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - PHYS 203: Climates/Climate Change - Spring 2002; folder 1 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - PHYS 203 - Spring 2002; folder 2 of 2 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - PHYS 203 - Spring 2002; Cheating Scandal (Confidential) (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - PHYS 203 - Spring 2004 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - PHYS 203 - Spring 2006; folder 1 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - PHYS 203 - Spring 2006; folder 2 of 2 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - SPAC 346: Atmosphere Weather and Climate - Spring 1991 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - SPAC 346 - Spring 1992 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - SPAC 443/MECH 477 - Fall 1983 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - SPAC 443/ENVI 443 - Fall 1985 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - SPAC 443 - Fall 1987 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - SPAC 443: Intro to Atmospheric Science - Fall 1989 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - SPAC 444 - Spring 1980/1984 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - SPAC 450 - Fall 1996 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - SPAC 512a - Fall 1972 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - SPAC 564 - Spring 1986 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - SPAC 603 - Fall 1984; folder 1 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - SPAC 603 - Fall 1984; folder 2 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - SPAC 603: Climate Dynamics - Fall 1988; folder 1 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - SPAC 603 - Fall 1988; folder 2 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - SPAC 604 - Spring 1987; folder 1 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - SPAC 604 - Spring 1987; folder 2 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - SPAC 606 - Spring 1985; folder 1 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - SPAC 606 - Spring 1985; folder 2 of 2 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - System Behavior and System Modeling (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - UNIV 200/300 - Fall 1998 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - UCAR (University Corporation for Atmospheric Research) Application - 1972 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - UCAR Application - 1984 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - UCAR Renewal - 1992 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - University of New Mexico Physics and Astronomy Colloquium Presentation: 11-19-1999 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - USRA-ESSA and NCAR-GCIP Workshop on Computer Modeling in the Classroom - July 1992 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Projector Slides/Film; folder 1 of 3 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Projector Slides; folder 2 of 3 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Projector Slides; folder 3 of 3 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Projector Slides/Photographs (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Projector Slides: Atmospheric Electricity (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Projector Slides: Lightning (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Projector Slides: Lightning Research (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Projector Slides: (Rice) Native American Course - New Mexico Field Trip (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Projector Slides: South Pole (Box 18, Folder 5)
- Series III: Martel College, 2000-2005
  Conditions Governing Access
  Some materials in this series are restricted. Please contact the Woodson Research Center for questions regarding access. 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu.
  - Martel Construction (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Martel Crest, Logo, etc. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Martel Furnishings (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Martel Owners' Meetings (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Martel Security (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Martel Founding Committee, etc. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - George Miner (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Martel Correspondence (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Copier - Xerox (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Martel Associates (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Martel RA Search (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Wine Testing (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - New Colleges Committee (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Martel Early Planning (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - M and P Meetings - Notes (Restricted) (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Masters with Gillis - 4/18/01 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Martel Budgets (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Martel Web (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Housing (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - New Student Applications - Fall 2001 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Student Recruitment (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Late Applications (>12/1/00) (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Transfers Fall 2001 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Final Transfer List by College (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - M and P August 30 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Martel Coordinator - Maria Byrne (Restricted) (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Martel Move In (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Martel House (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Martel Mtgs, E-mails (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Martel Opening (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - Events/Calendar (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Masters Meetings 2003-2004 (Restricted) (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Martel Courses (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Rice University Honor System (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - O-Week 2004 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Martel Course Spring 2004 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Joel Wolfe (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Martel Matters (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Greece (Martel Course) (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Martel Awards (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - College Course Fall '05 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - College Course Spring '05 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Awards (Box 21, Folder 11)
  - Visiting Scholar Apartment (Box 21, Folder 12)
  - Alcoholic Beverage Forms (Box 21, Folder 13)
  - Phill - Parliament (Box 21, Folder 14)
  - Dorm Room Makeover (VHS) (Box 21, Folder 15)